the Gate of Youth why is this gate very
important the gate begins from the age
of 12 all the way to
28 that's the gate called
youth it begins from 12 to
28 psych psychologically you need to
understand that between the age of 1 to
around 11 12 you are in a space called
the innocent stage the innocent stage I
love my daughter I love my son my
daughter is four my son is 2 and a half
years there's an age called terrible two
where they cry without
cause the boy can just wake up and cry
and they're not tears he's just walking
crying and now my daughter is four years
and what I've discovered in that age we
are controlling everything about their
lives one day I saw how my my wife had
dressed my daughter I said I wish I wish
she will see herself when she's
13 but purple
socks
blue shorts and a very heavy jacket that
was gray and then my wife told her you
look smart and she left boldly knowing I
look smart you cannot tell me anything
and we all remember those days where
some of us who grew in real African
homes our mothers will make the sweaters
and one is written I love Mom and I love
dad and will walk in church holding
hands and no one will tell you anything
you didn't have control over your life
they will tell you a horse is a dinosaur
and you look at a horse and say dinosaur
because you are so innocent whatever you
are told you believed now this is the
challenge as you continued
growing as you continued growing when
you are growing with your parents you
are growing with what we are called
dependency they decide your food they
decide what you wear they decide
everything even if you don't like pink
you'll find yourself wearing pink and
that stage you depend on them for
everything and they said that age the
mind of a child has developed to around
99% so when you enter 13 years the brain
begins to develop and something is
formed in your brain and they call it
the cognitive
ability not only is the brain developing
but even the body is now developing they
call it adolescence the adult Essence
what is that you feel like an adult but
you're not an adult but you have
feelings of an adult now life does not
answer to
feelings can we talk so so the adult
Essence is that you have the essence of
an adult you feel like an adult you feel
like a grownup and the truth is you are
growing and the first development is in
your mind it is called it's a it's it's
a folding in the brain that causes
something called cognitive ability what
is cognitive ability now you can
recognize you can know this is a horse
is not a
dinosaur and and that cognitive ability
begins to separate you from what we call
dependency to language of
Independence the stage called youth
now I don't know about you but I believe
African mothers are
Universal you just carrying the glasses
to the
kitchen and the mother will tell you
break all of them you're not the one who
buys
them those are Universal
mothers and and something in you answers
her but not
verbally because for the sake of
Peace you cannot tell her I
know but there is an answer from your
heart so what I'm trying to say some of
you you have submitted but your heart is
still
independent Hallelujah and that is why
there is a lot of conflict between
parents and their children when they
enter teenagehood
because no parent will ever believe you
are mature enough to be
independent this one day I shared an
idea with my mother at my age I'm
married and I shared an idea with her
and she lectured me for 30
minutes and I answered her in my
heart so allow me to tell you this no
matter how old you become your mother
will never sit
please that one just understand that
early no matter how big you become a
rugby player basketballer taller than
you are everyone there's no one day they
will ever see you as a grown-up because
they they still see the person who
dependent on them now the problem is
this stage called youth attracts
attention from heaven and from Hell the
second thing your life your future is
shaped by how you handle your youth
stage in short the future has begun how
you handle your youth stage matters a
lot a report has been done many people
who are in addictions they began in the
youth stage many people who are in jail
they began their mannerism while in the
youth stage so this is a recruitment
stage and there are five se's that
dominate in the youth's gate 5c number
one it is the stage of
conflict is the stage of conflict when I
when I talk of conflict is both inside
conflict and outside conflict is the age
of conflict even you you don't know what
you want in life when I went to school I
was told some people came as doctors
they will leave as
patients you literally wanted to pursue
um a career in becoming a doctor but
because you don't know what you want
some of you right now when your parents
ask you so what do you want to do and
you're like I want to be a DJ and
they're like are you mad DJ we we
investing all this money to become a DJ
and then you add salt to the injur and
say even a dancer and they're like what
happens if both of your legs are
broken one wise man told me use what is
in your pocket to put something in your
head one day what is in your head will
put something in your
pocket and I discover That's The Power
of
knowledge now is an age of
conflict and the devil likes it because
people are trying to discover
themselves people are trying to know
themselves outside the parameters of
supervision I don't want anyone to tell
me who I am I want to know me for me and
the word world is always waiting to tell
you who you
are and if you're not grounded in
identity chances of becoming who you are
not are very
high no one was born as a drunkard there
is no child who came on Earth and he or
she was given breast milk and said M and
then they were given heekin they said
that's it now no
one everything in life you learn and if
you can learn you can and
learn that's the rule of
life and so the devil is eagerly waiting
and do you know what happens at this
time you everyone does not want the
supervision of parents so at this time
it is pi that pierce your
destiny it is now people who also don't
know who they are that are trying to
tell you who you
are it's a is a stage of conflict
I remember in form two I don't know what
grade it is here I wrote my first Dis
Track because I wanted to do hip-hop and
I wrote my first hip hop dist truack to
my father and the song was called to all
the
haters because my father told me I am
not raising any rapper in this house
without a degree you are useless and I
realize this man is standing on the path
of my destiny I wrote a song called to
all the
haters and one day my mother asked me
now because you're a Nar
show me one rapper that has made it in
in music I began to mention people in my
age am& name toak Shakur and she was
like no no no leave America leave UK
here Kenya mention
one and I remember that conflict lasted
for so long that the first time I hugged
my father was during my graduation when
I received my degree in BSC geology and
and we prepared each other my dad told
me let's greet each other the church way
so I hugged him as if he was burning it
was the shortest but the most memorable
hug why because I thought the man was
against my life there is an African
proverb that says an old man sees father
while sitting than a young man
standing there is something that comes
with age and one day my dad came in my
office and he he looked at me and I told
him you are my hero if you never became
t with me then life would have taught me
something because this age people want
freedom and they want to explore and
they want to be rebellious so this is
the place of what we call Tough
Love otherwise all the people in my
youth that were given that open check to
become who they are today they are
either addicts or mothers that cannot
see who impregnated them and that's why
sometimes I love to have parents
sometimes open rebuke is better than
hidden love it's better someone who look
you straight in the eye and tell you the
truth than someone who massages you
knowing you're walking in the wrong path
are you listening to me and it was chaos
today my dad is my best friend I always
see down and tell him Dad thank you for
being that man who was tough and
unreasonable because if you reasoned in
My Level I will not be where I am today
and today I want to appreciate all the
unreasonable fathers and mothers one day
you
remember there was a song I was
listening from is it Elevation Worship
it's called I'm talking to Jesus and the
man sang and he said you know what my my
mama will drag me to church when I was
15 and I was mad and I didn't want even
to sing but he told me son talk to Jesus
and he said many years later I thank my
mother for taking me to church because
now I'm talking to
Jesus somebody say the age of
conflict listen the best thing you can
do in that age is to understand two
things you are living in rented
space he that pays the bills has the
say that that's the real I I'll help you
because these conflicts have to end and
you need to understand your parents are
not against you they have the best
interest in your
life someone said he that has the knife
and the arm dictates the size of what
you can eat so they have both the knife
and the Y and some of you in that
borrowed space you have your space it's
called your bedroom and you've already
set rules in your
bedroom especially the ladies if the
small brother comes and messes up with
your bed World War II has begun and you
are in borrowed space but you have made
rules that is to tell you every house
has rules
even the small space you have you have
created what rules so make sure you
learn early to live peacefully with
everyone and to understand dynamics that
everyone is not like you because the
greatest relationships you can keep is
with the people that are very close to
you never think we love you no I once
got suspended from school and the
teacher asked me now that you're being
suspended is anyone on Riot because
you're going home I looked at my peers
people are busy with their lives and I
realized I came alone I shall live alone
the only person that matters in your
life are sometimes the people you think
don't matter if you end up in jail it is
that same mother that same father that
will Camp there not your peers your
peers might might take selfies and say
hey let's pray for so and so the second
thing is a stage
of conf Chaos
the stage of chaos many things go wrong
in this
place many people lose their virginity
in this stage let's have a church many
are caught in masturbation pornography
in this stage I don't know why they call
this a cell phone could it be is a small
jail is a
cell this one will take many to
hell they say right now there are more
than 60 million pornographic sites
globally
many young people abound in masturbation
oh we're going to say this in
church because the enemy has
understood that what you need to do is
baptize them with
last last is genuine desire for sex that
is met in a genuine way and I've dealt
with many people and I can tell you
these a global crisis I I I met a person
who said my husband began masturbating
when he was 11 years old by the time he
was 28 and he got married he had what
they were calling l p count so he can't
be a father because he wasted his life
and there is such an arrest concerning
this matter and it will not surprise me
because this is an island surrounded by
water so this must be a territory that
is very active when it comes to the
Marine power and one of the signs of the
Marine power is not just sex is
perversion
sexual perversion very high so I
wouldn't be surprised if pornography is
highly consumed in this territory and
this what I discovered allow me to share
this there is a spirit called
asmodus asmodus is the demon responsible
for all sexual perversion and sometimes
it might manifest as a Night Demon I
know science will tell you oh you are
having a we dream but spiritually those
are demons that are trying to release a
spirit of last many people who try to
get out of masturbation they get attacks
of that spirit because the core business
of that spirit is attack you in a time
where you are not conscious and plant a
seed of last so he's a cycle the second
thing we have tried to pray for people
that are bound with pornography and
masturbation we've tried to pray for
them and sometimes is very hard for them
to be delivered is a very serious matter
because when that Spirit arrest you it
comes with what we call legality of
operation what is legality of operation
when I came here I had an invitation of
high heights I remember the first day I
came and I sat there so if anyone was to
come and kick me out I will fight not
because I'm a member of this church but
because I was invited so I will say no
but I've been invited Pastor camo
invited me so anytime we go to a
pornographic site I I was a victim allow
me to share my testimony I got initiated
when I was in I think class four that
should be around 10 12 years very young
and I wrestled until I decided to do a
research on that thing and some of the
sites I will open a site and see welcome
to the Devil's Kitchen when I got born
again is when I understood what this
means so these are not sites when you
open it on the phone it's like a demonic
portal a portal is a demonic gate that
allows transactions of spirits I
remember one day I was so tired with
pornography to a point I went to church
when pregnant women were being prayed
for all I knew I needed prayer so the
man of God said all the pregnant women
come and I was there because I was like
Lord Do not pass me by but I knew I'm
not pregnant but I need something until
I discovered I needed to participate in
my Deliverance so the first thing I
needed to release every pornographic
material for God to release Grace to
walk that's why someone came with a
phone and said pastor this is my problem
I told them put it here we have a place
in church where we help people to put
their phones and we tell them now go on
a pre without the phone and be delivered
because your first Deliverance is not
prayer your first Deliverance is
participation so they have what we call
legality of operation are you getting me
and now that spirit will now plant ideas
you might grow as a virgin in church
remember the daughters of lot were
virgins in Sodom but they went and slept
with their father outside Sodom in Sodom
men were having sex with men but there
was no case of people sleeping with
their
parents so the daughters of lot went and
slept with their parents because the
enemy is not afraid that you're a virgin
the enemy is afraid that there is no
idea of perversion in your mind that's
why we see people enter college and they
change 360 because in their stage of
Chaos there was incubation of
Madness oh
Jesus this stage the enemy is very
strategic part of the thing I've done a
whole research on secular
music I discovered sound is a vehicle of
spirits that's why we worship the Holy
Spirit could not move in Genesis until a
sound was released God say is a sound
and then he began to move and in this
world every sound will direct you to an
altar that's the reality that's why
there was a golden Cal Exodus and then
there was music you can't have worship
without sound every sound leads you to
an altar in the days of Daniel they said
listen when you hear this music sound
bow to the image of Bazar I did my own
research on hip hop rager um what they
call rock and roll and I discovered
every sound has a demonic element and in
these last days it is the days of
earphones there are two gates that the
devil is attacking in chaos the ears and
the eyes what now we are entering into
audio visuals uh these uh 7D and 3D kind
of conversations and I tell you the
truth we need to be very Vigilant am I
speaking to anyone we need to be very
Vigilant you need to take care of the
gates of your eyes and the gates of your
ears is a stage of Chaos is someone
getting me and that's why your
preservation is only in the Lord someone
came and asked me pastor but I've been
praying why is this addiction not going
out why is God not helping me I realized
let let me let me let me demonstrate
this this is what happens can I use you
for an for an example just stand this is
what happens just stand here come the
this Ro come all of
you let me demonstrate this stand in the
middle and I I love your spirit oh my
God you sing with a lot of passion
surround her surround her surround
her I mean make a circle around her yes
wow this is you now hold hands this is
how the life of a teenager looks like
sometimes you're dealing with secular
music dealing with peer pressure you are
dealing with um you know pornographies
all on your side all these things are
surrounding your life let's assume let
me use a physical language phys physics
language let's assume the energies you
dealing with are around 1,000 wattage or
let me put 100 wattage and your prayer
life can only produce 20 wattage it
means whatever you are generating cannot
overpower what is overpowering you and
that's why once in a while by the
prayers of our parents they are able not
to not to fully break just stop holding
hands by their prayers they're able to
disengage the powers that surround you
but you need to understand the prayers
of your parents will keep you forever
but because as you grow these forces
become stronger just hold your hands so
what needs to happen if she has the
capacity to generate 150 wattage of
spiritual voltage and whatever is coming
is 100 now this is what we call
Victory this is what we call Victory
when I how did I get out of addiction I
mastered the lifestyle of
prayer I began to fast sometimes I will
just fast without any prayer I will stay
a whole day until tell the Lord I am
here then I found a formula in the bible
where jesus found them sleeping and he
asked them why can't you T just for an
hour meaning that in prayer one hour is
called
just and then he says so that you may
not fall into
temptation meaning that if a young man
wants to be serious with their walk they
must Master prayer and and not 5 minutes
1 hour and one of the dimensions is
praying in the Holy
Ghost you need to look for good
headphones put worship and pray in the
spirit the kind of vibrations and energy
you produce from the spirit nothing in
your environment can bring you
down but you see one of the most hated
session is
prayer we can't deliver you from here
and this is why now we are having a very
oppressed generation this this is a
candidate of suicide by depression this
one can be a PhD holder but she doesn't
know peace because whatever she's
dealing with cannot be understood
intellectually this is Powers she can't
go to work without a bottle of alcohol
she can't go she cannot or he cannot do
anything without watching pornography so
we have taken care of the mind he the
they are healthy they have the right
medication but the spirit is sick and
this is where the devil is leading a
generation and this is how we are going
to conquer prayer is part of our
lifestyle every Friday always have
prayers in church and we always have
what we call one hour of tongue we call
it zaga zaga
Festival there's a real you make prayers
to look cool and we always tell the
young people two by two hold hands and
those that are not filled with the Holy
Ghost we begin by feeling them until
they pray in
tongues and after that we tell them one
hour and we time and then we go for a
relay 10 minutes 10 minutes 10 minutes
and I tell you I have seen young men
that are radical and I believe that that
Dimension ought to come because this is
the victory remember if this are spirits
Spirits don't die now let me show you
how people survive the let's assume she
has gone for three days of prayer and
fasting and she has broken she has
separated just go back go back go back
this is how young people survive now she
has Freedom she can move after after
moving now go now this is now stay there
don't go outside stay there yes there
now she has made some steps and then she
goes back to spir spiritual Slumber
Netflix show marks funny movies funny
songs guess what her spiritual energy
goes down and these things don't die
they come back so this is the life of a
young person victory defeat Victory
defeat after such a conference they are
on fire they even want a they even want
a crusade after two weeks they are
prayer
items that's why she must have the power
to
sustain that momentum is someone getting
me she must have the power to and this
is the victory of young people because
your parents may not cover you forever
you jesting is very personal Hallelujah
somebody say the stage of chaos chaos
you will win in this
chaos number three thank you thank you
and you're winning in Jesus
name number
three number three is also the stage of
confusion so we have conflict chaos
confusion many wrong decisions are made
in this stage you hear people say you
know I was was young and
stupid so young is not an excuse It's a
stage of
confusion number four is a stage of
curiosity oh my God how does it
feel and then you know there's this
conversation you know these old foxes
they keep on telling us not to do it yet
they did it in their day is only a fool
that lears by
experiment some things are irreversible
you can't you can't experiment there are
things you do and once you enter that
level it's
reversible some accidents you can't
reverse them this and that's why I say
this is the age of
recruitment because the devil Masters on
your
curiosity many addicts will tell you
they began when they were young that
that's the
pattern and in this level the Curiosity
can also be tamed for Godly
things it can also be tamed for Godly
things number five I'm just giving you
the five
Cs of the stage called Youth and then
I'll give you the three questions that
everybody must answer and then we'll
make a prayer are you learning something
are you learning something please tell
that neighbor you will not be a youth
forever tell that person you'll be a
youth once
so take advantage of
that
Hallelujah also I discovered the the
stage of a youth is the stage of
conquering this the stage of
conquering there are people who conquer
in their youth and the future is already
guaranteed a lady came and told me
Pastor I don't have a testimony asked
her why I've never drunk I've never had
sex I've never done those things you
call sin so she told me I want to do
them so that I can have a
testimony because you know when we come
here we keep on telling you a very dark
and ugly past those are not testimonies
those are called demonic hijackings the
Lord can preserve you like Samuel that
wine has never entered your mouth and
you are a Nazarite from birth anyone
that tells you this what we did me
included that is a demonic hijacking and
that's not a testimony there are people
who never never got out so don't think
that you are unique I mean don't think
that you are different in fact it means
the hand of the Lord has been upon your
life some of the drugs people take they
get born again with damaged kidneys some
get born again with damaged liver they
live with the consequences of their
mistakes they live with scar so if the
Lord can preserve you not to pursue some
path oh my God you are better and and
for me that's the generation I'm looking
for that will also have a pride month of
people walking and saying by the way I'm
a virgin and I'm 21 that is we need to
boast in the things that glorify the
father we need to be proud of who we are
someone looked at me and asked me so how
do you have fun I said what do you mean
you don't take alcohol you don't go to
these places where there's music I said
listen I love milk milk is good and
healthy I I go swimming once in a while
I go and play pool with my friends and I
realize it looks like positivity is is
not having fun you must go off for you
to look like you're having fun and we
can have what we call positive peer
pressure I have seen young people gather
and they gather for a prayer meeting the
whole night a young man was organizing a
birthday party and he turned it out to
be an evangelism party it is a birthday
everyone is in the neighborhood you
bring the sound you bring the music and
then you say let's hold hands and pray
for one minute and you hear everyone
praying in tongues and those who are not
praying in tongues begin to look and
they're like what I thought we were boys
I'm not telling you to look old you with
your with your Twisted hair rugged jeans
that's the generation sir don't don't
don't look
old leave the suits to us and
per yeah leave the dresses to
Mama you can be young and radical you
can be young and full of the Holy Ghost
you can be young and full of God
hallelujah that's why when the Lord was
looking for people people to work with
he never went to the old except Abraham
and you study the story of Abraham
you'll discover he had to introduce
youngness he had to be young after God
visits them in Genesis 20 the Bible says
the king of Geral went and took Sarah to
be a wife where are you taking a 99 year
old woman it means something had
shifted she had gone to s 16
any major business in Zion was not done
by old men it was done by young people
Mary at the age of 15 became the mother
of Jesus that's a teenager I know don't
bring human
rights different different states in
America I think in Texas you can be
married at
16 uh in se you can begin to drive at 16
and in another state you can even get
married at 21 so between 14 to 15 an
angel a oh God a girl was having Angelic
encounters by the name of Mary God is
ready to deliver a deliverer by the
pathway of a teenage girl is there a
girl that can say Lord disrupt my youth
because of your assignment this was a
disruption of a marriage and and the
woman was ready I spoke and I said John
was 17 years old the youngest apostle
entrusted with the mysteries of God
Daniel was between 17 to 19 when he
became a governor and there is no
civilization that could bring him down
you read the story of Daniel you're
looking at a 19-year-old Governor
advising Kings and Thrones being young
is not an excuse for
foolishness oh I am looking for 19y old
that are thinking different people that
have a global mind are thinking
Solutions someone said our greatest
misgiving is China created Tik Tok and
downloaded it to our people now our
people are doing Tik Tok challenge when
life is challenging
them a young man spends around 8 hours
on social media 8 hours to sleep and eat
and 8 hours to run life it means twoth
thirds of your life you have
wasted that man does not need prayer he
needs wisdom
oh Pastor I think in our home there's
generational curses no when you are busy
on Tik Tok men were building
lives David was 16 when he's killing
Goliath fighting National battles
16 I I just feel like asking at your age
what are you doing other than being a
wasapp ad
mean what is the other leadership that
you have received in your
life God is looking for young people to
partner with
Hallelujah God is looking for young
people to partner with tell that
neighbor you are not too young for
God do you know what the Bible says
Samuel used to sleep next to the Ark of
God at a very young age the boy used to
hear the voice of God I believe that
generation is coming that generation is
coming when you conquer the Bible says I
write to you because you are young why
you have overcome the devil there is a
conquering anointing you are strong
spiritual stamina there is victory in
this age whatever you conquer in your
youth you have conquered in your
future if you can manage women now you
will manage women in the future right
now you are poor money will bring them
like this
your DM will be full and maybe you're
going to be a manager of a serious
Enterprise and your problem right now
you're already polygamous you have four
exes you're not doing
well
Hallelujah it is the things we conquer
now a man wrote and said great men don't
leave for the future they live from the
future so the future is more complex it
has more opportunity the stamas are
developed now one day I attempted to go
to the
gym andl the word
attempt and I remember when I went to
the gym I was very vibrant I went with
my with my towel every time you can know
a first timer in the gym they always
overdressed with my snickers my shorts
and my my vest and I was there with a
ribbon on my head and I'm there then I
found a guy he was a little bit
overweight and he was Seated on the on
the reception desk and I said if this
the gym instruction I will not attend
because if gim has not worked for him
then it will not work for me then he
told me no I'm here I'm just a client
like any other person I said okay we are
many then the gym instructor came well
fed well muscled and all that then he
told me now for day one you just skip
the rope 200 times you do some few cut
wings and then you take this 2.5 kgs and
jump 50 times then you go home I felt
this is a wastage of time I can jump the
Rope at home I can do like this at home
and then he gave me the 2.5 I felt now
this guy is you know I'm a man 2.5 what
am I doing with it so after I was done
he said now you can hang around or go
home I went for 15
kgs I began to lift then I went for 50
then I went for 100 but that one was
Heavy then I went home the following
day the worst thing you will do is to
make a joke
the only thing I will do is vibrate
because if I laugh everything in my body
was
aching and so the gym instructor called
me and he told me where are you I told
him I cannot even lift my
hand he told me I told you you don't get
muscles
overnight you begin from the light
weights then go to the heavy weights and
then you can manage by yourself and he
told me this is the law of gy number one
consistency number two frequency and
number three I only demonstrate how to
LIF the weight but I can't lift the
weight for you because if I live the
weight for you the results will be on my
body and this is what I discovered about
life all we can do is demonstrate some
things but you must lift the weight for
yourself that's why there are challenges
that will come to you in your youth
stage but that's the weight you need to
lift because if you need results in your
life you must must lift the weight by
yourself this is the time you're
developing muscles not in the future
there are three questions that every
young man must answer number one who Am
I who am
I somebody said the best version of you
is revealed in the
dark I tell you if the lights go off
you'll hear some
screams and and sometimes if those
screams were to be begged to the people
you'll be surprised the people you
thought cannot even talk are the ones
who are going to
scream the the the the best way to know
who you are is when you are alone and in
the
dark sometimes we we know how to make
the masses happy but there's a reality
we can never fool
ourselves who am I what works for me and
this has to be answered from
appreciating what I cannot
change I discovered the the bone
structure of an elephant is different
from that of an
antelope I had weight issues when I was
young there are days I will even wear
three shorts and then a trouser just to
look like I'm okay and I will look more
thinner people will make jokes and say
you know what you need to put Pockets
you need to put stones in his pockets
just in case the wind takes him
until I came to the realization this is
my body I can't change it I remember I
met a young man and he was there with
his father he had a big head very
outstanding people used to call him head
boy and so one day they were watching
they were watching something with the
father and it was a preaching by rard
Bon and rard Bon said whatever you don't
like in your life put your hands there
and command it to leave and the young
man laid his hands on his head and the
father asked him what are you doing he
said I don't like my my
head please tell that neighbor what you
cannot
change sometimes that's What Makes You
unique are we together and and I want to
tell you that everyone is unique in
their own way I have a big nose so what
I enjoy
oxygen I have big ears so what I hear
things that people are not hearing I
have a big forehead yes I enjoy the
sunlight wait for summer
who am I but beyond saying who am I the
language of who am I is a language of
identity I tell you the truth if you
don't know who you are chances of
becoming who you are not are very
high if you don't know who you are
chances of becoming who you not are I've
met people who come and tell me pastor
this is not me it's the devil it's a
challenge of
identity and the first attack on every
man will be an attack over their
identity the Bible says Moses was raised
by two parents an Egyptian parent and a
Hebrew parent what were they trying to
interfere with
identity the Hebrew mother told Moses
you're a Hebrew the Egyptian mother told
Moses you're an Egyptian the Bible says
he was even taught with all the
literature of Egypt but one day he
needed to fight for his identity he came
across two people fighting an Egyptian
and a Hebrew and that picture was a
picture of Moses because in Moses there
were two people fighting a Hebrew and an
Egyptian and he had to kill the false
identity every young person will go
through that face every young person I
remember the first time I tasted alcohol
the thing was bitter I didn't like it I
tasted then I went under the table then
I came back said it's not even bitter my
face was light
because I was trying to fit in though I
didn't love it but a Time came and I
realized this is me water is
healthy I didn't even get born again to
stop drinking alcohol that thing is
bad it makes you wake up hanging over
towards hell I said
no and so just knowing yourself is a
very powerful thing knowing what works
for you even as simple as dresses
fashion not everything works for
everyone
I remember there was that we we were in
that stage of people wearing
pipes yes very tight things and some
people used to look funny because you
don't have the physique of tight
things you look like an ostrich okay
now we we we shouldn't be say some
things on the pulpit but am I speaking
to anyone am I speaking to anyone please
look yourself on the mirror and say this
is me I'm so unique and and God knew why
he created me the way I am there is no
one that has matching fingerprints even
twins identical everyone is very unique
and so the earlier you embrace your
uniqueness the better you are no
disadvantaged if you are fat that is
good occupy space and
time even the Bible says out of my belly
shall
flow so there are people who have enough
belly to flow
if you are thin appreciate that's you
Hallelujah because if you don't know who
you are chances of becoming you are not
are very high and now begin to set rules
that work for you who am I what works
for me because the moment you become a
people pleaser that's the time you lose
yourself in the equation of life you
must be number one no one will ever love
you more than you except Jesus no one
will ever take take care of yourself
more than you when my father discovered
I was smoking weed he called me and told
me listen you've not offended anyone in
this house when you smoke it doesn't
come out of your mother's nose when you
drink it doesn't land in my stomach he
said go and make peace with yourself I
don't think you love
yourself and I left that house and I
went and sat down and I asked myself do
I love me why am I taking something
written alcohol it will kill
you the manufacturer is telling me this
thing will cause cancer and I'm smoking
and I said but way don't love me so I
decided to love me
identity the Egyptian must die I wish we
could fight that battle but you have to
fight it you must emerge from what
people think someone said in the next
100 years none of us will be alive no
one will care what people thought about
you what people oh what people said
about in the next 100 years now imagine
not living life because of the
assumptions of men and life is not a
rehearsal you live
once you can please some people
sometimes but you can never please all
the people all the times the first
Deliverance is being not a people's
pleaser I don't care what people write
on my Facebook I update and I leave
because that was my idea so if you give
your idea it's your
idea number two the second question why
am I here there's something greater in
life why am I here it's the language of
purose it is either purose or Pumpers it
is either purose or
Pumpers if you don't know your purpose
it means you have nothing to live for
that means you can live for anything
sometimes it's not even the issue is not
our behaviors the issue is what's my
purpose why am I here what was I created
to do and you cannot know purpose
without God and and and and let me help
you there is a difference between your
your job and your
work God never created jobs a job is
what you are trained to do a work is
what you created to do an
example my work could be to help the
poor but my job is I'm an accountant so
I need my job to support my work is
someone getting me so jobs is what you
are trained to do
everyone here will need a good job a job
is what you're trained to do you are not
born as an accountant but work is what
you're created to do even at your young
age you still have empathy for the poor
you you have no money but there is
something that tells you you need to
help the needy that is now the work
every time you stand you want to preach
the gospel that's the work so there is a
work that needs a job to support but
many of us are lost in the job but
they've never discovered the work
and work gives you fulfillment a job
gives you
satisfaction are we together there's
something you do and you feel wow that's
so good you just Ser in the children
church and you feel wow the way those
kids were laughing you that gives you
Joy and the moment man loses his work
life becomes very miserable that's what
we call purpose are we together that's
what we call purpose what is it that you
can do
without even if we pay you what is it
that you can
do uh without uh you know appreciation
naturally you just do it that that's
that's the place of passion because for
you to know your P purpose you must know
your passion number one number two you
must know your talent and number three
you must know your gift those are some
of the things that will help you passion
passion is permission passion is that
thing you can do whether they are people
or not and you can do whether you're
being paid or not my passion was to rra
and I remember my one day my father took
away our radio and so my brother after
eating dinner will hit the table and
just create some instrumental doom doom
and then he'll tell me hey Buddha flow
and then I will go yeah
[Music]
yeah
[Applause]
R without a radio
they say some of the people you see
carrying a
guitar they don't know how to play it
but they are carrying a guitar and then
you'll ask them where are you going with
a G and then they'll say passion
passion passion is that thing you do
without uh being appreciated passion is
permission then there is Talent natural
ability that you are born with you don't
need Jesus to know your
talent some of you are talented software
Engineers you hold the for you see
things so it's not just the
extracurricular you can be talented in
many areas but now what crowns it all is
what we call a gift a gift you received
after spiritual birth a gift you receive
after spiritual
birth oh there are around 21 of them in
the Bible but we have no time of the
Father the Son and the gift of the
spirit like for me I'm a talented
speaker the gift that is upon my life is
the gift of apostol apostolic and then
the the passion is to see men
transformed that defines my purpose I
speak I love seeing people change and
then I have uh an Apostolic gift now
that makes me before I discovered my
Apostolic gift I used to organize all
the riots in high
school because I had a talent of
speaking and I had a Grace of mobilizing
people as young as class three I was
running a gang because I had the grace
to gather men so later when my gift was
discovered is when Ministry took shape
and my purpose took shape that's why
there are people who are in wrong areas
they have passion and they have talent
but it is the gift that will Usher them
to ordination and the final question you
need to ask yourself what can I do
potential what can I
do what can I do
potential tell that neighbor neighbor I
know something there is something in you
I don't know what it is but I know there
is something in you and is a great
thing
potential potential is innate abilities
or resident
abilities in a
being potential is innate abilities or
resident abilities in a being
now when you take maze it has the
potential to become a plant but there
are few factors that determine whether
potential will manifest or not everyone
has the power to be great but why is it
that everyone is not great write down
these factors number one factor number
one potential is environment
conscious potential is environment
conscious if you put a maze Bean on the
ground here and anoint an IT and pray
for it it will never grow because that's
not the environment you take the same
maze bean and put it on the ground
outside in three weeks you'll find a
maze shoot so we have to be environment
conscious I know possibly you've heard
about this there was a battle between
the lion and the
shark and and the battle was announced
and everybody wanted to know where it is
and they gave the credential the shark
is the beast in the sea it can turn you
into mist meat in less than 5 minutes it
has very sharp teeths and and you know
the the the size and the weight and all
that the lion the PO of a lion is 5 kgs
if you are hit by that PO you die
immediately and so there was war and in
the day of the battle the question was
very simple where was the environment
because in Sea the lion is a victim on
land the shark is a victim so
environment matters a lot some of you
cannot thrive in some places it's not
that you're not gifted like the the the
sister here who has been singing if we
take her to some secular environment she
may not Thrive because what she carries
is a holy seed but in church she will
Blossom so environment matters you could
be a lion doing business in the sea and
you could be a shark doing business on
land you never judge a fish by its
inability to climb CL a tree it was not
designed to climb a tree the second
thing potential is motion
conscious motion conscious in the laws
of physics there is kinetic and
potential energy I have seen good
machines packed there as it is packed
there it has the ability but until you
ignite and move it you can't enjoy that
ability that's why you must fight to
move many things will resist you in life
but but you must create a momentum to
perpetually move whether you are walking
crawling flying make sure there is
progress in your life are we together
that next year you'll not be where you
are this year because potential is
activated in motion the other thing that
fights potential is spiritual
warfare many people that have great
Destinies become a great Target of the
enemy some of the people you find taking
drugs that are very young age locate
them in the spirit you'll discover they
are very great in Mark chapter number
five there was a man in the tombs of
gines a man Jesus had a journey for that
man why that man that man was a
deliverer of 20 tensities called the
capis so the devil knew I don't need to
fight anyone intensities I need to fight
the deliverer imagine if in you there is
a supermarket and you're supposed to
employ 50 people the devil does not need
to fight 50 people he needs to carry the
employer of the 50 people that's why
when we bury young people we are not
burying young people we are burying
potential when I attend the Barry of a
young person I See Vision potential and
dreams being buried and I always cry
because I know every young man is a
carry of potential so potential is
environmental conscious are we together
potential is motion conscious potential
is
spiritual you spiritual warfare is a
target the other thing potential is
purpose conscious potential is purpose
conscious there are levels of ability
that you cannot manifest until you are
in the place of your
purpose that's why there must be
alignment of purpose for there to be
explosion of potential Hallelujah
alignment of purpose for explosion of
potential those are the factors that
hinder or control the manifestation of
potential